

SAMARTH JOSHI

ENGINEER (SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT)

CONTACT

Email

samarthjoshi1608@gmail.com

Phone

+49 15510218863

Address

Saarbrücken, Germany

SKILLS

- Python
- Machine learning
- Java
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Figma
- UI/UX
- C
- (++
- Laravel
- MS Office
- React.js
- Information Technology
- Microsoft Azure
- bug fixing
- Software Development
- software development practices
- application development
- Systems Engineering

ABOUT ME

Professional experience as a Computer Engineer in Systems Engineering, UI/UX, Software Development, Data Science, and AI/ML fields with different renowned companies Bachelor of Engineering in Computer with a thesis on the topic of Training and placement portal Multilingual: German, English, and two Indian languages

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Intern

January 2024 - March 2024

PrepInsta Pvt ltd. - Delhi

>Worked as junior data analyst intern.

>Worked on different data analysis/visualization projects based on python and implemented using python libraries such as Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly and also gained hands-on experience on different data analysis tools such as Tableau for designing visually appealing dashboards and visualizations.

Software Developer Intern

September 2023 - January 2024

Huawei Technologies Private Limited - Bangalore

- >Development in Text-to-speech conversion and recorder
- >Input validation, bug fixing, development and sanity testing
- >Write well-designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices.
- >Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems analyst

Front end design intern/UX Intern August 2023 - September 2023

Suven Consultants and Technology Pvt Ltd - Mumbai

- >Conducted user research, gathering feedback, and iterating on designs.
- >Utilized usability testing, analyzing behavior of {150+} users to gain insights.

TV - Samarth Joshi 1/2

LANGUAGES

English (C1) - Expert

German (A2) - Beginner

>Informed iterative design improvements, increasing user satisfaction by {15%} based on {60+} insights gathered

Systems Engineer (Information Technology)

July 2022 - August 2023

Tata Consultancy Services - Pune

>Worked with British Telecom and other financial institutions to address issues with various financial products

>Carried out various updates and resolved issues on the client system as needed and contributed to the application development for clients across the north america, europe, south east asia and the middle East.

>To do a routine system check to ensure no defects in the client system

EDUCATION

Master's Degree

2024 - present

Universität des Saarlandes, Computer Science - Saarbrucken, Germany

Bachelor's Degree

2018 - 2022

Savtribai Phule Pune University, Pune, India, Bachelor of Engineering (Computer) - Pune

Bachelor Thesis: Training And Placement Portal

My bachelor's thesis focuses on developing a training and job placement portal to simplify the job placement and placement-related industrial training processes. This project allowed me to demonstrate my abilities to manage the complete placement process via a user-friendly portal. The project is currently getting used by my bachelor's college, and over 500 students have currently enrolled on it.

CERTIFICATES

Big data analytics with Hadoop and Apache spark by Linkedlin Learning

Figma UI/UX web design and animation with six projects by Udemy

Microsoft Azure administrator associate

Foundations of user experience (UX) design by Google

Google IT support by Coursera

Introduction to IT Artificial Intelligence by Coursera

Python for data science and Big data foundations–1 by IBM

CV - Samarth Joshi 2/2